Lady Tamayo!
Good evening, Miss Tamayo.
It's dangerous, you know, leaving your window open at night like this.
I don't blame you, the moon is truly gorgeous tonight.
Nice to meet you. No need to worry. I'm one of Kaguya Ubyashiki's messengers.
I understand you have suspicions. I don't blame you.
I already assumed before meeting you that it would be hard to gain your trust the way Tanjiro has. Oh well.
What does he intend to do, Ubyashiki? Is he trying to deceive me somehow?
And Yushiro?
You have my word that Yushiro is safe.
Listen, you can hear his footsteps running towards us.
Lady Tamayo! Lady Tamayo! Lady Tamayo!
And now, shall I state my business here?
In the Demon Slayer Corps, there is a young girl who is also well versed in demon physiology.
We'd like you to collaborate with her and look into the changes to Nezuko.
Help us defeat Muzan Kibutsuji. The decision is yours.
We'll be waiting at the Ubyashiki Mansion.
You're summoning me, a demon, to the headquarters of the Demon Slayer Corps?
I'll be waiting for a favorable response from you.
Lady Tamayo!
Yushiro…
Let's clear out of the house now! I'm ready to go!
It's not like that.
Now that Nezuko has managed to conquer the Sun, something's been set in motion.
No. It's possible change was set in motion long before that.
What happened on that fateful day has at last begun to swell and become one large wave.
If that's the case…
It can't be, Lady Tamayo!
Either way, we will be leaving this house.
However, things are different this time.
I'm going to start compiling the research I've done up till now.
But I will need your help, Yushiro.
Quickly.
This may very well be our last move.
Now let's go to the Demon Slayer Corps headquarters.
The Ubyashiki Mansion.
Tagio and회衡 room five more minutes.
If I take the moment of permission now…
hidden from another ænd thisainsoue
one.
Already let's know the days of legacy.
I un societal columna.
Thank you!
make me
Master Tanjiro, how are your wounds healing
I'm ashamed to admit it, but I am no longer capable of moving.
And though I'd like to speak with Giyu myself, it doesn't look like that'll be possible.
As this is a very important time for us, I'd like to strive together as one as we push forward with all our might.
And so, would you mind being the one to talk to Giyu for me?
My hope is that Giyu, who burdens himself with negative thoughts, can start to look forward again.
So be persistent. Don't give up until he sees the light.
Mr. Giyu...
Yes!
It's awfully early, Mr. Tanjiro. Where are you heading?
Ms. Aoi.
Are you leaving? For Hashira training?
No, I'm not. But I have to see someone before that.
I guess that should be fine, then.
Ms. Aoi?
What is it?
There's something that I'd like to ask you. Is that okay?
Let's say that there's someone who feels like they're all alone.
How would you go about convincing that person that they're not alone?
Is there a way to do it while actually getting through to them?
Well, if anyone knows the answer to that, it's not me.
But Mr. Tanjiro, above all else, you want to cheer this person up, don't you?
Well, if it were me, I'd just want to be left alone.
By the way, are you leaving now?
Uh, yes.
Wait here a minute, okay?
Oh, are you going to visit just one person?
Yes.
This sure is complicated.
They're very simple, but I've made you some rice balls.
There should be enough for both you and that person.
Whatever you do, you need to eat your fill first.
Or else you'll never become healthy in body and soul.
Ms. Aoi, thank you.
Bye now!
Excuse me, Mr. Tomioka?
Hello?
Sorry to bother you.
Mr. Diyu?
It's me.
Are you in there?
It's me, Tanjiro Kamado!
Hello?
Alright, I'm coming in.
Coming in?
No.
He must have said I'm leaving.
I simply misheard.
No.
So, long story short, everyone's been busy training.
I know.
Oh, so you knew.
That's great.
Too close.
And I'll be cleared for active duty in seven days.
You think you can train me then?
I can't.
But why not?
I'm catching a faint whiff of anger from you.
But what could have you upset?
I'm upset that you never mastered water breathing to its perfection.
After all, you were meant to become the next water Hashira.
Well, look, I'm very sorry about that.
But I talked to Mr. Urokodaki about it.
Changing the style you started with to develop a new breathing technique apparently isn't all that uncommon.
And since water breathing moves are so in line with the fundamentals, it can spawn a lot of techniques.
That's not what I'm talking about.
We're still missing a water Hashira.
Someone has to assume the mantle, and I suppose I hoped it would be you.
Still missing a water Hashira?
But you're the water Hashira.
I'm not the water Hashira.
Get out.
So be persistent.
Don't give up until he sees the light.
Right!
Mr. Giyu!
I brought some rice balls with me.
Would you like to eat them together?
They say you can't be angry.
After a good meal and a full stomach.
All right.
I'll just leave them here for you.
Mr. Giyu!
You're up early.
You must have enjoyed those rice balls.
That's great!
Mr. Giyu!
Please wait!
Where are you headed, Mr. Giyu?
Mr. Giyu!
What are you up to?
Are you on patrol?
It does feel like demon sightings have settled down, doesn't it?
No demons here, huh?
Thank goodness!
So we can start training now!
Mr. Giyu!
Do you want to come training?
Training!
Everyone's waiting for you!
Mr. Giyu!
Mr. Giyu?
Oh, no!
Is this going to last forever?
Mr. Giyu!
If I talk to him, will he stop stalking me and leave me in peace?
Thing is, I never did pass the final selection.
Mr. Giyu!
What?
Wait, the final selection?
You mean the trial back on the mountain?
Mr. Giyu!
That's right.
I didn't take it alone.
There was a boy, whose family had also been killed by demons.
His name was Sabito.
I'll never forget his peach-colored hair.
Or what happened that day.
Sabito and Mr. Giyu.
Mr. Giyu, I was 13 back then.
Mr. Giyu, we were the same age and alone in the world.
We became friends quickly.
Sabito had a strong sense of justice and yet a kind and gentle heart.
Mr. The only one who died during that year's selection was Sabito.
He managed to kill nearly every demon on that mountain single-handedly.
In the end, everyone but Sabito passed that final selection.
As for me, I was left wounded by the very first demon that attacked me.
I was helpless.
At that moment, it was Sabito who saved me.
Water breathing. Fourth form. Striking tide!
After saving me, I was left in the care of another boy.
Then he quickly ran off towards another cry for help.
When I came to, the final selection was over.
While it's true I survived for seven days, therefore passing the selection,
I didn't kill a single demon and had only been saved by another.
And so, can you really say that I passed?
Someone like me isn't worthy of being the water Hashira.
I don't even deserve to stand next to the likes of the other Hashira.
I'm not like them.
Normally, there'd be no place for me in the Demon Slayer core.
Have the real Hashira train you.
It's for the best, really.
I'll never manifest a mark.
As for Sabito, there's no doubt he would have.
Just forget about me.
You're wasting your time.
I get it.
I really do.
I'm sure he thinks he should have been the one to die that day.
I know how that feels.
When someone you value more than your own life
ends up dying before you instead.
And worse,
dies because they were protecting you.
It's an unending pain.
Sabito.
The boy who trained me back on Mount Sigiri.
What a strange experience.
Even though they were both already long dead,
they taught me how to survive.
I see.
So Sabito went through final selection with Mr. Giyu.
If he survived, he'd be the same age as Mr. Giyu now.
Amazing.
He saved everyone during the selection.
Something I couldn't do.
I was barely able to protect myself.
If Sabito were still here,
I'm sure that he'd be an incredible swordsman.
That must be part of the reason
why Mr. Giyu feels he should have been the one to die.
I get it.
I had that same thought myself.
Mr. Rengoku.
He sacrificed his own life to protect us.
He was incredible.
His kindness rivaled his strength.
And he never faltered.
Right up till the end.
I wished with all my heart
that I'd been the one to die
instead of Mr. Rengoku that day.
I thought that one day
Mr. Rengoku might have been able to kill Muzan.
But...
He already said he believes in you.
So you just have to worry about how to get there.
Yes.
That's exactly right.
I know that.
But I'm not sure what I should say to Mr. Giyu.
No matter how pathetic or embarrassed you may feel,
you've got to keep living.
Though he doesn't acknowledge it.
I can't imagine how hard he must have trained
in order to make himself a worthy candidate for Hashira.
The amount of suffering he must have gone through.
It's not my place to criticize Mr. Giyu
when I know nothing about him.
But...
But there's one thing I have to ask him.
Only then...
Mr. Giyu!
Oh no, he's not stopping.
What's Sabito entrusted to you?
Aren't you going to pass it on?
Sa...
Sabito?
Don't you dare ever say that you should have died again!
Next time you say that, you and I are through.
It's unforgivable.
Your older sister,
who was supposed to be married the next day,
knew what was going to happen
when she hid you from that demon to protect you.
So how dare you insult her memory
by saying something so selfish!
You have to live
and carry her memory!
The life your sister gave you with her sacrifice,
the future she gave you,
you have to pass them on!
Giyu!
It hurts.
The shock and pain I felt when he struck me
is coming back to me now so vividly.
Why did I forget until now
that conversation with Sabito
when it's so important?
I didn't want to remember it
because I wouldn't be able to stop the tears.
Remembering
made my grief unbearable
and left me utterly helpless.
Big sis Tsutaku
Sabito
I'm sorry.
Oh no.
I think I finally broke him.
What do I do?
Was that too harsh of me?
Somehow he looks even more depressed
than he usually does.
Did I just end up making it worse?
I know!
How about a speed eating contest?
If I win the contest,
I'll say let's cheer up
and get some training in.
Or something.
Since I haven't been cleared
for active duty yet,
it's not like I can spar with him
or anything.
Mr. Giyu may not talk much,
but he wouldn't have to
during an eating contest.
It's brilliant!
Tanjiro,
I know it's a little late,
but I'll join the-
Mr. Giyu!
I challenge you to an eating contest!
Why?
Listen,
about the training program,
I didn't hear any mention of Kocho.
So what is it
that she's teaching you all?
Ms. Shinobu?
I haven't heard anything, actually.
I wonder how she is.
Calm down.
It's all right.
Big Sis,
help me to calm down.
Only the immature
are unable to control their emotions.
The immature.
Master,
you have returned.
I'll be departing now
to receive training
from the Lord Wind Hashira.
I see.
Can our training session
wait until after
the Lord Stone Hashiras?
Unfortunately,
I'm not going to be taking part
in the Hashira training.
Huh?
But-
But why?
Kanao?
Come over here.
Okay.
So, um,
you see,
I want-
I want nothing more
than to train with you,
Master.
Well, now,
look at you.
You've learned to be more candid
about giving voice
to your feelings.
That's a good sign.
As I thought,
the timing is perfect.
I'd like to tell you
about the demon
who killed
my beloved older sister,
Kanae.
and also
how to go about
killing the same demon.
I believe you're ready.
God bless you.
Thank you.
The Downloader Act
is not modiously
and your human violence
isn't it?
The
A
reason
Thank you
I
We turn around
We rely on our dreams
Just the desire can
As much easier as I am, and I want to be cloudy andumber at the time.
Thank you.
We'll be talking about Mr. Giyu this time.
I'm done eating more soba noodles.
I can't eat any more either, so no need to worry.
It's time for a Taisho era secret.
Mr. Giyu's haori, or at least half of it belonged to Sabito.
And the other half of it belonged to his older sister, Ms. Tsutako,
who was also killed by a demon.
That just goes to show you how tender he is.
Tanjiro, want some simmered salmon and daikon?
You really mean that?
Yes, but no racing.
I'd be happy to.
But first, next episode three,
fully recovered Tanjiro joins the Hashira training.